Guide to the W. Stephen Coleman Papers, 1981-2011 CTC.2011.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- University of Pittsburgh Repertory Theatre, 1981-2009; II.
  - Les Liaisons Dangereuses, 1995; 16.
    Les Liaisons Dangereuses was performed at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre, November 7-18, 1993.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Production materials, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Promptbook, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Colored Museum, 1996; 17.
    Coleman served as directing supervisor for The Colored Museum. Kenyatta Rogers directed the production. The play was performed February 22nd through March 2nd, 1996 at the Studio Theatre in the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Production materials, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hamlet / Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead, 1996; 18.
    Hamlet and Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead were performed in repertory at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre, November 1-23, 1996.
    - Production materials, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
    - Promptbook - Hamlet, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
    - Promptbook - Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 15-16)
    - Video recording - Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead, November 22, 1996; 1 cassette_tapes VHS (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Noises Off, 1997-1998; 19.
    Noises Off was performed at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre, April 1-19, 1998.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Production materials, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Promptbook, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, 1998; 20.
    Cat on a Hot Tin Roof was performed at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre, November 4-22, 1998. This production featured several songs by Pittsburgh native Ernie Hawkins. There are recordings of these songs on audio cassettes in the production materials folder.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Music, 3 cassette_tapes (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Photographs (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Production materials, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Promptbook, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Little Shop of Horrors, 1999-2000; 21.
    Little Shop of Horrors was performed at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre, March 29th through April 16th, 2000.
    - Production materials, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 11-13)
    - Promptbook, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - Waiting for Godot, 2001; 22.
    Coleman performed in and directed Waiting for Godot. He played the role of Estragon. The play was performed September 19th through October 7th, 2001 at the Henry Heymann Theatre in the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Production materials, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 17-19)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, 2002-2003; 23.
    Much Ado About Nothing was performed April 2-19, 2003. It was the inaugural production at the newly renovated Charity Randall Theatre, previously known as the mainstage of the Stephen Foster Memorial.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Music, 1 disc 25 minutes (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Production materials, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
    - Promptbook, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
  - Twelfth Night, 2003-2004; 24.
    Twelfth Night was performed at the Henry Heymann Theatre, March 31th through April 18th, 2004.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Music - Pre-show, 2 discs 41 minutes (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Music - Intermission, 4 discs 75 minutes (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Production materials, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Promptbook, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 11-13)
  - Arms and the Man, 2004; 25.
    Arms and the Man was performed at the Charity Randall Theatre, November 10-21, 2004.
    - Digital photographs (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Music, 2 discs 102 minutes (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Production materials, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 16-18)
  - Old Times, 2005; 26.
    Old Times was performed at the Henry Heymann Theatre, September 21st through October 9th, 2005.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Digital photographs, 1 disc (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Music - Pre-show, 1 disc 34 minutes (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Photographs (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Production materials, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Promptbook, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Chekhov Vaudevilles, 2006-2007; 27.
    Anton Chekhov's The Proposal, The Wedding, and The Bear were performed at the Charity Randall Theatre, March 21st through April 1st, 2007.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Photographs (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Production materials, 2006-2007 (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
    - Promptbook, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Count Dracula, 2008-2009; 28.
    Count Dracula was performed at the Charity Randall Theatre, October 22nd through November 1st, 2009.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Production materials, 2008-2009 (Box 12, Folder 4-6)
    - Promptbook, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Acting and Directing, 1981-2011; III.
  This series contains promptbooks and production materials relating to W. Stephen Coleman's acting and directing in the Greater Pittsburgh Area. Productions from City Theatre, Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre, Civic Organizations, Chatham College, and the Pittsburgh Playhouse are included in this series. Acting projects for the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival and Pitt Repertory Theatre are also included. Please note that there is one non-Pittsburgh production included. In 1981, Coleman performed in a production for the Austin Repertory Theatre, in Austin, Texas.
  - Austin Repertory Theatre - A Life in the Theatre, 1.
    In 1981, Coleman played the part of Robert in this David Mamet play for the Austin Repertory Theatre. He also served as the choreographer for the production.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Pitt Repertory Theatre - She Stoops to Conquer, 1981; 2.
    Coleman performed in She Stoops to Conquer as Mr. Hardcastle. The play was performed November 5-21, 1981 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Production materials, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - City Theatre - Shakespeare's Swashbucklers, 1981; 3.
    Shakespeare's Swashbucklers was a joint production of the City Theatre Company and Gateway to Music of fight scenes from Shakespeare's plays. Coleman directed the show and it toured Pittsburgh area schools during the 1981-1982 season.
    - Production materials, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - The Merry Wives of Windsor, 1982; 4.
    Coleman performed in The Merry Wives of Windsor as Frank Ford. The play was performed July 8th through the 24th, 1982 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Production materials, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - Hamlet, 1982; 5.
    Coleman performed in Hamlet as Claudius, King of Denmark. The play was performed June 17th through July 3rd, 1982 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Production materials (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - The Tempest, 1982; 6.
    Coleman performed in The Tempest as Sebastian. The play was performed July 29th through August 15th, 1982 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Production materials (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Pitt Repertory Theatre - Good, 1983; 7.
    Coleman performed in Good as John Halder. The play was performed October 19th through November 12th, 1983 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Production materials, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - ALCOA - American Society of Safety Engineers, 1984; 8.
    Coleman directed this industrial show for an ALCOA professional development conference in 1984.
    - Production materials, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - The Merchant of Venice, 1984; 9.
    Coleman performed in The Merchant of Venice as Antonio. The play was performed June 29th through July 21st, 1984 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Production materials, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - Love Labor's Lost, 1984; 10.
    Coleman performed in Love Labor's Lost as Ferdinand. The play was performed July 27th through August 19th, 1984 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Production materials, July 1984 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - Romeo and Juliet, 1985; 11.
    Coleman performed in Romeo and Juliet as Lord Capulet. He also was the fight choreographer for the production. The play was performed May 31st through June 22nd, 1985 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Photographs (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Production materials, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - Twelfth Night, 1985; 12.
    Coleman performed in Twelfth Night as Sir Toby Belch. The play was performed June 28th through July 22nd, 1985 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Production materials, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - All's Well That Ends Well, 1986; 13.
    Coleman performed in All's Well That Ends Well as Lafew. The play was performed June 27th through July 20th, 1986 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Production materials, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - King Lear, 1986; 14.
    Coleman performed in King Lear as the Earl of Kent. He also was the fight choreographer for the production. The play was performed July 25th through August 17th, 1986 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Production materials, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - City of Pittsburgh Bureau of Cable Communications - Citylife, 1987; 15.
    Coleman served as the co-host for this City of Pittsburgh public affairs talk show from 1986 through 1995.
    - Pittsburgh City Council proclamation, October 5, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - Richard III, 1987; 16.
    Coleman performed in Richard III as Lord Stanley, Earl of Derby. He also was the fight choreographer for the production. The play was performed July 24th through August 15th, 1987 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Production materials, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Pitt Repertory Theatre - Educating Rita, 1987; 17.
    Coleman performed in Educating Rita as Frank. The play was performed November 11-22, 1987 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Production materials, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival - Antony and Cleopatra, 1989; 18.
    Coleman performed in Antony and Cleopatra as both Lepidus and Dolabella. The play was performed July 21st through August 12th, 1989 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - At Last the World Says Yes, 1991-1992; 19.
    Coleman was an actor and reader for Samuel Hazo's At Last the World Says Yes. This production was performed at Westminster College in February 1992.
    - Photographs (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Production materials, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Until I'm Not Here Anymore!, 1992; 20.
    Samuel Hazo's play Until I'm Not Here Anymore! was directed by Coleman. This world premiere production was performed at the Fulton Theater, September 1-4, 1992. The production was adapted and filmed for local television. There is a VHS recording included in the subseries.
    - Production materials, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Promptbook, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
    - Slides and negatives (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Video recording, 1 cassette_tape VHS, 90 minutes (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Theatre at Hartwood - One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest, 1993; 21.
    One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest, was directed by Coleman. The Theatre at Hartwood production was performed August 10-28, 1993.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Promptbook, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Slides (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater - Dybbuk, 1993-1994; 22.
    Coleman performed in Dybbuk as both Nachman and Judge. The play was performed December 30th, 1993 through February 6th, 1994 at the Theodore L. Hazlett, Jr. Theater.
    - Production materials, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Theatre at Hartwood - Sleuth, 1994; 23.
    Coleman performed in and directed Sleuth. He played the role of Andrew Wyke. The Theatre at Hartwood production was performed September 14th through October 23rd, 1994.
    - Promptbook, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Pitt Repertory Theatre - Marat/Sade, 1997; 24.
    Coleman performed in Marat/Sade as the Marquis de Sade. The play was performed November 5-23, 1997 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Production materials, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Film project - Achilles' Love, 2000; 25.
    Coleman played the part of Constantine Zoras in the film Achilles' Love. The film was shot in Pittsburgh and was released in 2000.
    - Newspaper clippings, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre - The Picture of Dorian Gray, 2000; 26.
    This production of The Picture of Dorian Gray was directed by Coleman for Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre. The play was performed August 10-26, 2000 at the City Theatre Mainstage.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Production materials, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 15-18)
  - Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre - Portia Coughlin, 2001; 27.
    Coleman appeared in this production of Portia Coughlan as Sly Scully for Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre. The play was performed March 22nd through April 7th, 2001 at the Eddy Theatre at the Chatham College campus.
    - Production materials, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre - Tartuffe, 2001; 28.
    Coleman appeared in this production of Tartuffe as Orgon for Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre. The play was performed June 14-30, 2001 at the City Theatre Mainstage.
    - Production materials, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre - The Seagull, 2001; 29.
    Coleman appeared in this production of The Seagull as Dr. Hickey for Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre. The play was performed August 9-25, 2001 at the City Theatre Mainstage.
    - Production materials, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Pitt Repertory Theatre - How I Learned to Drive, 2002; 30.
    Coleman performed in How I Learned to Drive as Peck. The play was performed October 31st through November 10th, 2002 at the Studio Theatre in the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Production materials, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Creative Nonfiction Foundation - Diversity Dialogues Series, 2003; 31.
    Coleman directed the readings at several of the installments of the Diversity Dialogues Series of the Creative Nonfiction Foundation.
    - Audio recording - Diversity Dialogues (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Production materials, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre - Henry IV, 2005; 32.
    Coleman appeared in this production of Henry IV as the Earl of Warwick for Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre. The play was performed April 20th through May 14, 2005 at the Charity Randall Theatre in the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Production materials, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Film project - John Dunn's Last Run, 2006; 33.
    Coleman played the title character's father in the short film John Dunn's Last Run. The film was shot in the Johnstown area in 2006 and was released by Firefly Entertainment in 2009.
    - Production materials, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater - Oedipus the King, 2006; 34.
    Coleman performed in Oedipus the King as Egeon. The play was performed September 28th through October 29th, 2006 at the O'Reilly Theater.
    - Production materials, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre - Julius Caesar, 2007; 35.
    Coleman performed in Julius Caesar as both Cicero and Volumnius. The play was performed April 11th through 28th, 2007 at the Charity Randall Theatre in the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
    - Annotated acting edition (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Production materials, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater - The Comedy of Errors, 2007; 36.
    Coleman performed in The Comedy of Errors as Egeon. The play was performed October 4th through November 4th, 2007 at the O'Reilly Theater.
    - Production materials, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater - Amadeus, 2008; 37.
    Coleman performed in Amadeus as Baron Gotfried van Swieten. The play was performed January 24th through February 24th, 2008 at the O'Reilly Theater.
    - Production materials, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
  - The Father, 2008; 38.
    Coleman directed a staged reading of the August Strindberg play The Father. This performance took place September 22nd, 2008 in the Henry Heymann Theatre. It was a one night only performance and was not a part of the University of Pittsburgh's Theatre Arts Department schedule that season.
    - Production materials, September 22, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater - Stayers and Goers, 2007-2008; 39.
    Coleman performed in a reading of the Todd Kreidler play Stayers and Goers as Mye Peters. This performance took place November 17th, 2008 in the O'Reilly Theater Rehearsal Hall.
    - Production materials, November 17th, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater - Harry's Friendly Service, 2009; 40.
    Coleman performed in Harry's Friendly Service as Carmine Naples. The play was performed May 28th through June 28th, 2009 at the O'Reilly Theater.
    - Production materials, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 12-14)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 2010; 41.
    Coleman performed in A Midsummer Night's Dream as Egeus/Peter Quince. The play was performed January 21st through February 21st, 2010 at the O'Reilly Theater.
    - Production materials, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater - Camelot, 2010-2011; 42.
    Coleman performed in Camelot as Merlin. The play was performed January 20th through February 20th, 2011 at the O'Reilly Theater.
    - Production materials, 2010-2011 (Box 14, Folder 16)